Say , is this the moving-picture ship ?
The Venture ? Yeah .
- Are you going on this crazy voyage ? - What 's crazy about it ?
I don 't know . But everybody is talking about that crazy fella running it .
- Carl Denham ? - Guess that 's the name .
He ain 't scared of nothing . If he wants a picture of lion
he just goes up to him and tells him to look pleasant .
He 's a tough egg . Why all this talk about this voyage being crazy ?
Everybody around the docks is talking about the cargo , for one thing .
And I never did see a ship this size with such a crew .
- Not enough men to handle her ? - Not enough !
Three times more than the ship needs .
I don 't see where they 're gonna have room enough to sleep .
Hey , down there . What do you want ?
- Denham aboard ? - Who are you ?
My name is Weston , the theatrical agent .
Well , why didn 't you say so ? Come on aboard .
Denham 's getting wild . I hope you 've got some good news for him .
Well , Mr. Denham , you know the reasons for hurrying as well as I do .
Insurance company found out we 're carrying explosives .
Marshal will be aboard tomorrow or next day .
If we make a legal case of it , we 'll be tied up for months ?
With enough ammunition to blow up the harbor .
What do you think the marshal will say to these new gas bombs of yours ?
According to you , one of them is enough to knock out an elephant .
We 've got to get where we 're going before the monsoon starts .
- Trust me to see you through a blow . - Oh , now , don 't get sore , skipper .
You can 't run into the rainy season when you 're trying to make an outdoor picture .
Months wasted , money gone and nothing to show .
Still you always bring back a picture .
And everybody says , " There 's only one Carl Denham . "
Weston , I was just going ashore to call you .
If I 'd known that , I would have waited .
This is the skipper . Weston , the theatrical agent .
I guess you met Driscoll , the first mate .
Well , Weston , how about the girl ?
- It can 't be done , Denham . - What ?
It 's got to be done . Now , look here , Weston .
Somebody 's interfered with every girl I try to hire .
Now all the agents in town have shut down on me . All but you .
- You know I 'm square . - Everybody knows you 're square .
But you 've got a reputation for recklessness
that can 't be glossed over . Then you 're so secretive .
You said it .
Even skipper and mate don 't know where they 're going , what .
There you are . I 've got a conscience , Denham .
I can 't send a pretty girl such as you ask on a job like this
without telling her what to expect . - What is she to expect ?
To go off on a trip for no one knows how long
to some spot you don 't even hint at
the only woman on a ship with the toughest mugs I ever looked at .
I mean the crew .
Good Lord , you talk as if I never brought anybody back alive .
The skipper and Driscoll have stuck to me on two trips .
- They look well enough . - Sure , we 're healthy .
But it 's a different thing taking a girl into danger .
I suppose there 's no danger in New York .
Listen , there are dozens of girls in this town
that are in more danger than they are with me .
Yeah , but they know that kind of danger .
You never had a woman in any of your pictures .
- Why do you want one ? - Holy mackerel !
Do you think I wanna haul a woman around ?
- Then why ? - Because the public , bless them
must have a pretty face .
Sure , everybody likes romance .
Isn 't there any romance or adventure without having a flapper in it ?
Well , Mr. Denham , why not take a picture in a monastery ?
Makes me sore . I go out , sweat blood to make a swell picture
then the critics and the exhibitors all say :
" If this picture had love interest , it would gross twice as much . "
The public wants a girl , and this time I 'm gonna give what they want .
- Don 't know where you 'll get her . - I 've gotta get her , Weston .
We 've gotta leave by morning .
- We 've gotta be gone by daylight . - Why ?
Well , there 's a good reason .
Everything I hear about it makes me like it less .
I 'm glad I didn 't get you a girl .
You are , eh ? Well , I 'll show you .
Do you think I 'm gonna give up because you can 't find me a girl ?
I 'm going to make the greatest picture in the world .
Something that nobody 's ever seen or heard of .
They 'll have to think up a lot of new adjectives when I come back .
- Where you going ? - Going out
and get a girl for my picture . Even if I have to marry one .
- Stand aside , please . Get your case later . - Can I take my things ?
Say , lay off the shoving , will you ?
- Oh , I didn 't mean to shove you . - Excuse me .
What do they give you in this joint ?
Soup tonight . Coffee and sinkers in the morning .
I catch you , you stealer . Now , I get you cop . You like that , huh ?
No , no . I didn 't . Let me go . I wanted to , but I didn 't .
- Had enough of these stealers . - Dry up . Kid didn 't take any .
- Truly I didn 't . - Three people this week ...
- Here ... Here 's a buck . - A buck .
Scram .
Hey , taxi !
Feeling better ?
Yes , thank you .
- You 're very kind . - Don 't you fool yourself .
I 'm not bothering about you just out of kindness .
- How 'd you ever get into this fix ? - Bad luck , I guess .
There are a lot of girls like me .
- Not many with your looks . - I can get by in good clothes all right .
- But when a girl gets too shabby ... - No family ?
Supposed to have an uncle someplace .
Did you ever do any acting ?
I used to do extra work now and then over on Long Island .
The studio 's closed now .
- What 's your name ? - Ann Darrow .
Fine . I 've got a job for you .
Costumes on the ship will fit you .
If the shops are still open , I can get clothes for you .
- Come on . - But ...
- But what is it ? - It 's money and adventure and fame .
It 's the thrill of a lifetime . A long sea voyage
that starts at 6 : 00 tomorrow morning .
No , wait .
I don 't understand . You must tell me .
I do want the job so
but I can 't . - Oh , I see .
No , you 've got me wrong . This is strictly business .
- I only wanted ... - Sure . Sure you did .
I got a little excited and I forgot you didn 't understand .
Listen , I 'm Carl Denham . Ever heard of me ?
Yes , yes . You make moving pictures in jungles and places .
That 's right . And I pick you as lead in my next picture .
We sail at 6 .
- Where to ? - A long way off .
And listen , Ann , I 'm on the level . No funny business .
- What do I have to do ? - Just trust me and keep your chin up .
Hey , you men on that winch
down below on the deck and help with these hatches .
Hurry this line forward .
Forward , you farmer and up here !
What are you doing up here ?
- I just wanted to see . - Oh , you just wanted to see .
Well , I 'm sorry . Make that line fast !
You 're that girl Denham picked , aren 't you ?
Yes . I think this is awfully exciting . I 've never been on a ship before .
I 've never been on one with a woman before .
I guess you don 't think much of women on ships ?
No , they 're a nuisance .
- I 'll try not to be . - You 've been in the way already .
Bring that ladder aboard !
Well , you better stay below .
What ? The whole voyage ?
I 'm afraid I didn 't apologize for hitting you .
That was a pretty tough rap on the chin .
- Well , we 're off . - We 're off .
Say , how many potatoes do you think you 've peeled in six weeks ?
Too many .
Sailors eat an awful lot , don 't they ?
All time eat . Someday me go back China .
Never see no more potatoes .
- Charlie , isn 't the ocean wonderful ? - Very pretty .
Pretty soon you be all same sailor , only no eat so much .
I 'd like to be . Only , of course , it wasn 't so nice up north
when it was cold and rough was it ?
Ocean very nice when you order weather or some eggs for breakfast .
- Hello , Ann . - Hello , Jack .
Where you been all morning ?
Trying on costumes for Mr. Denham .
He 's gonna make some tests of me here on deck
if the light is right . - Tests , why ?
Oh , to see which side of my face looks best and all that .
Both sides look all right to me .
Yes , but you 're not the movie director .
If I was , you wouldn 't be here .
Well , is that a nice thing to say .
This is no place for a girl .
I wish you wouldn 't keep harping on that . It 's very mean of you .
Anybody would think I 'd been a lot of trouble .
I haven 't . You can 't say I 've been one bit of trouble to anyone
have I ?
- Sure you have . Sure you have . - I don 't see ...
Well , how ?
Just ... Just being around is trouble .
Oh , dear , and I thought everything was going so nicely .
Oh , you 're all right .
But women just can 't help being a bother .
- Made that way I guess . - Well , anyhow ...
I 've had the happiest time of my life on this old ship .
That 's ... That 's fine .
Say ...
Did you really mean that , Ann ?
Of course . Everyone 's so nice to me . Dr. Denham and the skipper ...
Don 't you think the skipper is a sweet old lamb ?
I 'd hate to have him hear me say that .
Iggy 's nice to me .
Iggy likes me better than he likes anybody onboard .
Don 't you , Iggy ?
- That 's right . Of course you do . - Beauty and the beast , eh ?
Well , now , I never thought I was good-looking .
Put on one of the costumes . The light 's right for those tests now .
All right , Mr. Denham . I won 't be a minute .
Beauty and the beast .
Mr. Denham
I 'm gonna do some butting in .
- What 's your trouble ? - When do we find out
where we 're going ? - Pretty soon .
Will you tell us what happens after ?
How can I ? I 'm not a fortuneteller .
You must have some idea what you 're after .
What 's the matter ? You going soft .
Oh , you know I 'm not . Not for myself .
- For Ann . - Oh , you have gone soft on her , eh ?
I 've got enough troubles without a love affair to complicate things .
- Better cut it out , Jack . - Love affair .
- Think I 'm gonna fall for any dame ? - I never knew it to fail .
Some big hard-boiled egg gets a look at a pretty face , bang
he cracks up , gets sappy . - Who 's going sappy ?
I haven 't run out on you ?
No . You 're a pretty tough guy .
But if beauty gets you , you ...
I 'm going right into a theme song here .
- Say , what are you talking about ? - It 's the idea of my picture .
The beast was a tough guy too .
He could lick the world , but when he saw beauty , she got him .
He went soft , he forgot his wisdom and the little fellas licked him .
Think it over , Jack .
Mr. Denham , skipper wants you up on the bridge .
- He says we 've reached the position . - Good .
Come on , Jack . You 're in on this . I 'm gonna spill it .
There 's our noon position . Two south , 90 east .
Now , you promised some information when we got here .
- Way west of Sumatra . - And way out of any waters I know .
I know the East Indies like I do my own hand
but I 've never been here . - Where do we go from here ?
- Southwest . - Southwest ?
Well , there is nothing for thousands of miles .
Keep your shirt on , skipper . We 're not going thousands of miles .
Here 's the island we 're looking for .
Well , that position . Let 's have the big chart .
You won 't find that island on any chart .
That was made by the skipper of a Norwegian bark .
- He must have been kidding . - No , he wasn 't .
Listen , a canoe full of natives from this island was blown to sea .
When the bark picked them , there was one alive .
He died before they reached port , not before the skipper
had a description of the island and got an idea of where it lies .
- Where did you get it ? - Singapore , two years ago .
Skipper knew I 'd be interested .
- Does he believe it ? - I don 't know . But I do .
Here . Here 's what the island looks like .
There 's a long , sandy peninsula .
The only possible landing place is through this reef .
Rest of shoreline 's sheer precipice , hundreds of feet high .
And across the base of the peninsula , cutting it off
from the rest of the island , is a wall .
- A wall ? - Built long ago . People who lived there
slipped back , forgotten the high civilization that built it .
That wall is as strong today as it was centuries ago .
The natives keep that wall in repair .
- They need it . - Why ?
There 's something on the other side of it . Something they fear .
A hostile tribe .
Did you ever hear of Kong ?
Why , yes .
Some native superstition , isn 't it ? A god or a spirit or something .
Well , anyway , neither beast nor man
something monstrous , all-powerful .
Still living
still holding that island in a grip of deadly fear .
Well , every legend has a basis of truth .
I tell you , there 's something on that island that no white man has ever seen .
- And you expect to photograph it ? - If it 's there , you bet I 'll photograph it .
Suppose it doesn 't like having its picture taken ?
Well , now you know why I brought along those cases of gas bombs .
Oh , you 've put on a beauty-and-beast costume , eh ?
It 's the prettiest .
All right . Just stand right over there .
I 'm sort of nervous . Suppose I don 't photograph well ?
You don 't have to worry about that . If I hadn 't been sure
I wouldn 't have brought you around the world .
- What will I do ? - Well , we start with the profile .
When I start cranking
why , hold it a minute , and then turn slowly toward me .
You see me . You smile a little , then you listen .
Then you laugh . All right .
Camera .
- Looks kind of silly , don 't it ? - Pretty dame , huh ?
You think maybe he like to take my picture ?
Them cameras cost money . Shouldn 't think he 'd risk it .
Now , that 's fine , Ann . Now we 'll try one with a filter , eh ?
Do you always take the pictures yourself ?
Ever since a trip I made to Africa .
I 'd have got a swell picture of a charging rhino
but the cameraman got scared .
The darned fool . I was right there with a rifle .
Seems he didn 't trust me to get the rhino before it got him .
I haven 't fooled with a cameramen since . I do it myself .
- Think he 's crazy , skipper ? - Just enthusiastic .
Ann , in this one you 're looking down .
When I start to crank , you look up slowly .
You 're quite calm . You don 't expect to see a thing .
Then you just follow my directions . All right ?
Camera . Look up slowly , Ann .
That 's it . You don 't see anything .
Now look higher
still higher .
Now you see it . You 're amazed .
You can 't believe it . Your eyes open wider .
It 's horrible , Ann , but you can 't look away .
There 's no chance for you , Ann , no escape .
You 're helpless , Ann , helpless .
There 's just one chance , if you can scream
but your throat 's paralyzed . Try to scream , Ann , try .
Perhaps if you didn 't see it , you could scream .
Throw your arm across your eyes and scream . Scream for your life .
What 's he think she 's really gonna see ?
This infernal fog . Sure of your position , skipper ?
Last night before this fog shut down , I got a good sight .
We should be near the island .
If we don 't see it when this fog lifts , we never will .
We 've quartered these parts .
Can 't see your hand in front of your face .
Hey , Charlie , I wish you 'd make your soup as thick as this .
No bottom at 30 .
The Norwegian skipper must 've been guessing at the position .
How will we know it 's the right island ?
- The mountain that looks like a skull . - Oh , yes , I 'd forgotten . You told me .
- Skull Mountain . - By the deep 20 .
Shallowing fast . Mr. Briggs , dead slow .
Dead slow , sir .
- Confound this fog . - By the deep 16 .
- What 'd she draw , skipper ? - Four .
Why don 't he heave to until it clears ?
'Tain 't the old man . It 's that crazy guy , Denham .
Listen , you hear anything ?
No .
- Breakers ahead . - Let go .
That 's not breakers . That 's drums .
Skipper , now the fog 's lifted , do you see anybody ?
- Not a living thing . - Funny they haven 't spotted us .
I 'd think the whole population would be on the beach .
Listen .
Maybe they have spotted us and are signaling .
Well , skipper , do you believe me now ? There it is .
Skull Mountain , the wall .
Everything just like on my funny little map .
- Come on . Let 's get started . - All right .
Twelve men go with you . The rest stay aboard .
Have you got a good man with those gas bombs ?
I think you better go along .
You may be able to talk to these birds .
All right . Mr. Adams .
Aye , sir .
- You 'll take charge of the ship . - Aye , aye , sir .
- I 'm going ashore with you , aren 't I ? - You bet .
I don 't think she should until we know what 's there .
Wait a minute . Who 's running this show ?
I found out from experience to keep my cast and cameras with me .
You never can tell when you 'll want them .
- But you 're crazy to risk ... - Jack
run along and get the rifles and ammunition .
And get me a couple of huskies to carry my stuff .
And , Jack , don 't forget the costume box .
If we 're lucky enough , we may get a swell shot right away .
Come on , Ann .
All right , boys , let 's go .
- Take it easy with that camera . - Okay .
- Plenty of ammunition for those guns ? - Yes , sir .
Be careful with those bombs .
All right , Briggs , now we 'll get a look at Denham 's island .
Stand by to lower away .
You with the camera , stick close .
- Okay . - Who 's got the bombs ?
- I have , sir . - Watch your step .
There 's enough trichloride to put hippos to sleep .
Aye , aye , sir .
- What queer-looking boats . - Yeah , outrigger canoes .
Driscoll , I want two men left here to guard the boat .
- All attended to , sir . - Good .
We all ready , then ? Come on .
Not a soul in sight .
The people must all be gathered up ahead .
That wall , skipper . What do you think of that ?
Colossal . It might almost be Egyptian .
But what 's on the other side of that wall ? I wanna know .
Who do you suppose could have built it ?
Oh , I was up on Angkor once .
That 's bigger than this , and nobody knows who built it .
Oh , boy , what a chance . What a picture .
Come on .
Hear that ? They 're saying , " Kong , Kong . "
Hope you talk their lingo , skipper .
- You catch any words yet ? - I 'm not sure .
Sounds something like the language Nias Islanders speak .
What do you suppose is happening ?
They 're up to some of their heathen tricks .
But don 't go rushing out to sea .
- All right . But isn 't it exciting ? - Sure .
- I wish we 'd left you on the ship . - Oh , I 'm so glad you didn 't .
Wait . Easy , now . Wait till I see what goes on .
Holy mackerel ! What a show .
Hey , skipper , come here and get a load of this .
Did you ever see anything like that before in your life ?
Boy , if I could only get a picture before they see us .
Hey , you with the camera . Come here .
I wanna see .
Come on , but be careful .
- Too late . They see us . - Let 's ... Let 's beat it .
- Hey , what are you running for ? - No use trying to hide now .
Everybody come out in plain sight .
- Say , let 's scram out of here . - Stand still , you fool .
Steady , boys , bluff them .
Come on , skipper . Make him a friendly speech .
He understands you , skipper . What 's he say ?
- He 's telling us to get out . - Well , talk him out of it .
Ask him what goes on .
He says the girl there is the bride of Kong .
Great . Find out what they 're gonna do .
- What 's that ? - He must be the witch doctor .
He says the ceremony is spoiled because we 've seen it .
Well , calm the old boy down . What 's the word for friend ?
Steady with those rifles , boys .
- What 's that ? - He says , look at the golden woman .
Yeah . Blonds are scarce around here .
- A gift for Kong , he says . - Good Lord !
Wants to buy her .
He 's offering to trade six of his women for Ann .
You got her into this , Denham .
I 'm gonna take her back to the ship .
We 'd better get out of here before they think to cut us off .
Guess so . But tell him we 'll be back tomorrow to make friends .
Get going , Ann . Don 't be scared . Everything 's all right .
Smile , Ann , and talk to Jack .
Keep your chin up .
- Say , why aren 't you in bed ? - Oh , I can 't sleep .
The sound of those drums makes me nervous , I guess .
I think Denham 's off his nut taking you ashore today .
Well , I was a little scared .
- I guess you weren 't the only one . - I wonder what we do next .
That 's just what 's worrying me .
Denham 's a fool , there 's no telling what he might
ask you to do for this picture .
After all he 's done , I would take any chance for him .
Don 't talk like that .
I 'd say he 's crazy enough to try anything .
Well , I won 't go back on him .
When I think of what might 've happened today , if anything had happened to you ...
Then you wouldn 't be bothered having a woman onboard .
Don 't laugh . I 'm scared for you .
I 'm sort of ... Well , I 'm scared of you too .
Ann ...
I ...
Say ...
I guess I love you .
Why , Jack , you hate women .
Yeah , I know . But you aren 't women .
Say , Ann ...
I don 't suppose ...
I mean ...
Well , you don 't feel anything like that about me
do you ?
Mr. Driscoll , are you on deck ?
Yes , sir .
Will you please come up on the bridge ?
You go on . I 'll wait here .
Yes , sir .
There , that 's about it .
We 'll make absolutely sure tomorrow noon .
Oh , must be almost midnight .
Hey .
Look at that .
Torches going through the village .
Yeah , looks like the night before election .
Listen to them . Wonder what 's up .
Wish I could take pictures by firelight .
- I 'd sneak ashore and get a scene now . - Oh , be sensible .
We 're lucky to be all safe aboard tonight .
Yeah , I guess so .
- Charlie , have you seen missy ? - Me no see one , two hours .
When we leave this place ? Me no like .
Ann .
All hands on deck ! Everybody on deck !
Everybody on deck ! All hands on deck !
Everybody on deck ! Everybody on deck !
- What 's the matter ? What 's happening ? - What 's going on ?
- What 's the matter ? - I 'm out here .
Look , sir . Me find on deck .
- A native bracelet . - Crazy black man been here .
What is it ? Who turned out the crew ?
- Look . Someone 's been aboard . - Where 's Ann ?
- In her cabin . - No , she isn 't . I just looked .
- What 's the matter , Mr. Driscoll ? - Search the ship . Find Miss Darrow .
Aye , aye .
- Ann . Oh , Ann . Did you see her ? - No .
I 'll look below .
- Did you find her ? - Can 't find her forward .
- She 's not below . - Can 't find her aft .
Ann 's gone !
Serve out the rifles . Man the boats .
Take this ammunition outside .
Come on , you fellas . Grab these guns .
Take these bomb cases and be careful with them .
Pass those rifles up over the side .
Start packing those bombs .
Me likey go too . Me likey catch missy .
This is no job for a cook . Get out of here . Come on .
Shove her off , men . We 're going over the side .
Give way , gentlemen . Right over there .
They 've taken Ann .
Hurry . Hurry up . She must be up ahead here .
- Come on , men . - Come on , boys .
Has anybody seen her ? Come on .
Get this gate open . Quick !
Get up there , men . Pull that thing back !
Pull that bar back . He 's got Ann .
Heave . Heave .
- Who 's going with me ? - I 'll go .
You stay with half the men and guard the gate .
- Don 't let them close it . - We 'll take care of it .
No telling which way he went in this darkness .
He 's been through here .
- Look at these broken branches . - Yeah , look at that . Keep up , fellas .
It ought to be sunup about now .
Yeah , just listen to those birds .
It 's dawn all right .
- What 's that ? - Holy mackerel !
Yeah , that 's his track . Look at the size of that thing .
He must be as big as a house .
He 's headed this way .
Come on , fellas , and keep those guns cocked .
Hate to have that thing wrapped around me .
Here 's another one . We 're on his trail .
Sure , sure . I know that . Come on . Come on , fellas .
Hey , look at that !
Keep quiet . He doesn 't see us .
Give me one of those bombs .
Look , it 's gonna charge .
Keep quiet .
Come on .
Give him another one .
Look out !
Look out . He 's still alive .
Shoot .
Come on . That got him .
What do you call this thing ?
Why , something from the dinosaur family .
Dinosaur , eh ?
Yes , Jack
a prehistoric beast .
Say , just look at the length of that brute .
If I could only bring back one of these alive .
- Watch that tail ! He 's still alive . - Come on , looks like he 's standing up .
He 's through . Come on .
Come on , men .
Boy , one swipe of that .
- Hear that ? - Yeah . What is it ?
That 's him , boys . Come on .
Here . Here 's his mark again .
- There 's water ahead . - He 's down in that fog somewhere .
Yes , that 's him splashing through . Come on .
Be careful .
Now , watch the step-off , boys .
Must have swum across .
Yeah , it 'll be tough for us with these guns and bombs .
- What about these logs for a raft ? - Good idea .
Come , fellas . Get busy .
Put those guns down on the bank and get going .
Move !
Come on with those poles .
All set , everybody ?
Shove off !
- Hear anything ? - No , he 's miles away by now .
We 'll be able to pick up his trail all right .
Listen .
Quiet .
What was it ?
Hang on , men .
Look out . Here he comes .
Come on .
Hey , Jack . Jack Driscoll .
- Hey , Jack . - Denham .
- It didn 't get you , huh ? - No , I got to cover , same as you .
- Think we 're safe ? - There are two of us
left alive to save her . - I can 't get across now .
Don 't want you to . Lam back and get more bombs .
Why , you wouldn 't follow that beast alone .
Someone 's gotta stay on his trail .
I 'll get a chance , sneak her away .
I 'll figure a way to signal you where he 's taken her .
- I guess that 's our only out . - Sure it is . Get going .
Don 't get killed till you see Englehorn .
Okay , Jack . Good luck .
Skipper , this Kong is the biggest thing in the world .
He shook those men off that log like they were flies .
All those men lost . It 's incredible .
Driscoll said he 'd try and signal us if he found Ann .
- We 'll never see them again . - Don 't give up .
- There 's chance for Driscoll . - Wait for daylight .
We 'll bridge the ravine . Where 's that case of bombs ?
- Here , sir . - This ...
This monster you 've seen , you think your bombs will stop him ?
If we can get close enough to use them , you bet they 'll stop him .
- Had any trouble with the natives ? - Yes , after you left .
- What happened ? - We fired volleys over
their heads , they ran like rabbits .
Gunpowder 's new in their lives ?
- They 're terrified . - They haven 't shown up .
Take a man on the wall , keep your eyes peeled .
We leave at dawn , if we get a signal or not .
Yes , sir .
Hey , look .
Hey , below , Mr. Denham . Captain Englehorn .
Mr. Driscoll and the lady , they 're coming back .
Come on , fellas .
Are you both all right ?
Pint , Jack . Here .
I 'm all right .
What happened ? How did you do it ?
- Came down the river . - Oh , Jack .
There , there , you 're safe now .
We 'll have you back on the ship in no time .
Wait a minute . What about Kong ?
Well , what about him ?
We came to get a movie , and we found something worth
more than all the movies in the world . - What ?
We 've got those gas bombs .
- Lf we can capture him alive ... - Why , you 're crazy .
He 's on a cliff where a whole army
couldn 't get at him . - Yeah , if he stays there
but we 've got something he wants .
Yeah , something he won 't get again .
Hey , look out . It 's Kong . Kong 's coming .
Come around . Come here and hold the gates . Quick .
- Denham , natives are coming . - Good work . Come on .
Hey , come back with those bombs , you ...
Come on . Come on . I got him .
He 'll be out for hours . Send to the ship .
- For anchor chains and tools . - What will you do ?
A raft to float him to the ship . The whole world will pay to see this .
- No chains will hold that . - We 'll give him more than chains .
He 's always been king of his world , but we 'll teach him fear .
We 're millionaires , boys . I 'll share it with all of you .
In a few months , it 'll be up in lights on Broadway :
" Kong , the Eighth Wonder of the World . "
Say , what 's Denham got anyway ?
It better be good after all this ballyhoo .
Heavens , what a mob .
Well , you would come . These tickets cost me 20 bucks .
I can 't sit so near the screen . It hurts my eyes .
This is not a moving picture , madam .
What ? Mr. Denham makes those pictures
of those darling monkeys and tigers and things .
This is in the nature of a personal appearance .
Well , I never . I thought I was gonna see something .
- Say , what is it anyhow ? - I hear it 's a kind of a gorilla .
Gee , ain 't we got enough of them in New York ?
I don 't like to look at him .
It makes me think of that awful day on the island .
I wouldn 't have brought you , but you know how Denham insisted .
We had to come when he said it would help the show .
Do you think we 'll make a lot of money ?
Well , enough to pay him back for these clothes anyway .
It 's the first time I ever had on one of these open-front suits .
Hello , there . Just in time . Gee , Ann , you look great .
I 'm glad I dressed you up for this show . Well , Jack , $ 10,000 in the box office .
- Not bad for one night . - That 's a lot of money .
We 're gonna do that every night .
- Look at the size of that . - I hope he 's tied up tight .
Sure he is . Denham 's taking no chances .
Here are the press . Come in , boys .
- This is Ms. Darrow and Mr. Driscoll . - How do you do ?
Mr. Driscoll saved you from the ape ?
Yes . He was alone too . All the sailors with him had been killed .
- How did you ever tackle that baby ? - Well , Mr. Denham got him .
The rest of us were running scared .
He had the nerve to stand there and chuck bombs .
Oh , so you 're the hero . Come on , give us a story .
Here now , wait a minute . Lay off me , boys .
Miss Darrow is the story . If it hadn 't been for her
we couldn 't have gotten near Kong . He followed her .
- Beauty and the beast , huh ? - That 's it .
Play up that angle , beauty and the beast .
Kong could have stayed safe
but he couldn 't stay away from beauty .
- That 's your story , boys . - That 's a lead story , all right .
- How about some pictures ? - Just a minute .
Come on the stage . Take pictures in front of the audience .
I 'll make a speech and tell them about Kong , Darrow
Driscoll . When I call you , come take pictures .
- Okay . - That 's fine .
Stand by , Ann , when I call you .
Now , now , it 's all right .
We 've knocked some of the fight out of him since you saw him .
Ladies and gentlemen , I am here tonight to tell you a very strange story .
A story so strange that no one will believe it .
But , ladies and gentlemen , seeing is believing
and we , my partners and I
have brought back the living proof of our adventure .
... an adventure in which 12 of our party met horrible deaths .
And now , ladies and gentlemen , before I tell you any more
I am going to show you the greatest thing your eyes ever beheld .
He was a king and a god in the world he knew
but now he comes to civilization merely a captive
a show to gratify your curiosity .
Ladies and gentlemen , look at Kong .
The Eighth Wonder of the World .
And now I want to introduce Miss Ann Darrow
the bravest girl I have ever known .
There the beast and here the beauty .
She has lived through an experience no other woman ever dreamed of .
And she was saved from the very grasp of Kong by her future husband .
I want you to meet a very brave gentleman , Mr. John Driscoll .
And now before I tell you the full story of our voyage
I will ask the gentlemen of the press to come forward
so that the audience may see them take the first photographs
of Kong and his captors .
All right , boys .
Miss Darrow first , alone . Stand in front of Kong , Ann .
- All set ? Make it a good one . - Okay .
Shoot .
Don 't be alarmed . Those chains are made of chrome steel .
- It 's all right , Ann . - Get them together , boys .
- They 're going to be married tomorrow . - Put your arm around her , Driscoll .
Wait a minute . Hold on .
- He thinks you 're attacking the girl . - All the roaring , swell picture .
Come on , it 's loose !
Send the riot squad and ambulances . Kong has escaped .
You 're safe now , dear .
It 's like a horrible dream .
It 's like being back on the island again .
Now , it 's all right . Don 't worry .
I 'm gonna stay right here with you .
Anyhow , you know they 're bound to get him .
Jack , he 's climbing up outside there .
- He 's got Ann . He 's taken her up . - The roof , quick .
Ann , Ann !
How can we follow him ? What 'll we do ?
Fire department searchlights on the roof .
Yeah , they 'll keep him in sight .
Attention all stations . Kong is going west .
He is making for the Empire State Building .
Stand by for further reports .
- Lf he goes up there , what can we do ? - We won 't get near him .
Kong is climbing the Empire State Building .
He is still carrying Ann Darrow . That is all .
That licks us .
- One thing we haven 't thought of . - What ?
Airplanes . If he should put Ann down
and they fly close to pick him without her ...
You 're right . Planes .
Call the field .
- Here come the planes . - They 'll get him .
- Can they shoot him and not hit Ann ? - They 'll be shooting .
Ann . Ann , hang on , dear .
- Ann , are you all right ? - Jack !
Just a moment . Wait a minute .
Let me through . My name is Denham .
Just a moment . Oh , lieutenant .
- Lieutenant , I 'm Carl Denham . - Carl Denham .
Denham ? Oh , that 's the man that captured the monster .
Well , Denham , the airplanes got him .
Oh , no , it wasn 't the airplanes .
It was beauty killed the beast .
[ ENGLISH ]